Register of the Aleksandr Fyodorovich Kerensky Miscellaneous Papers, 1945-1965
Hoover Institution Archives
Aleksandr Fyodorovich Kerensky miscellaneous papers,
1945-1965
72001
Kerensky, Aleksandr Fyodorovich, 1881-1970
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence and writings, relating to the Russian Revolution and personal matters. Includes a history by Kerensky, entitled "The Genesis of the 'October Revolution' of 1917", and correspondence with Vasilii Maklakov, Michael Karpovich and Anatole G. Mazour.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research. Use copies of all sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access.
Access Points
Russia.; Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Statesmen--Russia.; Karpovich, Michael, 1888-1959.; Maklakov, V. A. (Vasilii Alekseevich), 1870-1957.; Mazour, Anatole Gregory, 1900-
Biographical Note
1881 Born, Simbirsk, Russia
1904 Called to the St. Petersburg bar
1912-1917 Member, 4th State Duma
1917 March Minister of Justice in the provisional government under Prince G. E. Lvov
1917 May Minister of War and Navy
1917 July Prime Minister
1917 November Fled St. Petersburg
1919 Author, The Prelude to Bolchevism: The Kornilov Rebellion
Author, Soviet Russia in the Autumn of 1919
1927 Author, The Catastrophe
1934 Author, The Crucifixion of Liberty
1940 Settled in the United States
1965 Author, Russia and History's Turning Point
1970 June 11 Died
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1917-1965 (Box 1)
  Handwritten and typewritten letters, organized alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - Unidentified (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aldanov, M., 1948 (Folder 2)
  - Anisimov, G., n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Berberova, Nina, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Ivanov, G. B., n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Karpovich, Michael, 1956-1959 (Folder 6)
  - Maklakov, V. A.
    - Undated (Folder 7)
    - 1945-1949 (Folder 8)
    - 1950-1953 (Folder 9)
    - 1954-1957 (Folder 10)
  - Mazour, Anatole G., 1961-1965 (Folder 11)
  - Pipes, Richard, 1959 (Folder 12)
  - Radkey, Oliver, 1957 (Folder 13)
  - Rumkies, 1948 (Folder 14)
  - Souvarine, Boris, 1951 (Folder 15)
  - Terent'ev, Vladimir, 1959 (Folder 16)
  - Tetiukova, Pavla, 1917 (Folder 17)
  - Miscellany, 1956 (Folder 18)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
  Typewritten manuscript and discussion transcript, arranged chronologically by title
  - "The February Revolution Reconsidered," 1957 March 12. Typewritten transcript of discussion with Leonard Shapiro (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "The Genesis of the 'October Revolution' of 1917," 1961. Typescript (Folder 20)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1959 (Box 1)
  Telegrams received relating to the death of Michael Karpovich
  - Telegrams received relating to the death of Michael Karpovich (Box 1, Folder 21)
- SOUND RECORDINGS (Box 1)
  Use copy reference number: 72001_a_0000080_a
  - Alenxander Kerensky speech, 2005 August 4 (Box 1)
    Speech presented by Mills College and the San Francisco Foundation